

 \searrow

sakshamsingh06a@gmail.co



+91-9756876750



Noida, India



linkedin.com/in/saksham-s-690863100

SKILLS

SQL

UI/UX Testing

Functional Testing



Databases

Java

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hind

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Swimming

Socializing

Travelling

Music

Photography

Saksham Singh

Quality Assurance Engineer

Meticulous Functional Tester with extensive career in Testing Software Applications and Identifying areas in need of improvements. With around 2 Years of Experience in Software Testing, developing skills to become a change maker and a corporate leader, and to be enterprising and dynamic in approach.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd.

11/2020 - Present

Noida, India

Responsibilites

- Testing of Vehicle based Website & Application
- Create Test Plans, Test Scenarios, Test Cases and Documents
- Reporting Defects and Bugs on Jira Platform
- Categorizing tasks and their Priorities
- Creating QA Reports for better User Interface and Experience of the Application
- Retrieving data from Database using complex SQL Queries

QA Manager: Suraj Tahiliani - suraj.tahiliani@tcs.com

System Engineer Intern

Infosys Ltd.

02/2020 - 03/2020

Mysore, India

Achievements

 Successfully completed Two months training as System Engineer (Intern) at Infosys Ltd, Mysore DC

CERTIFICATES

ANDROID APP DEVELOPMENT

Attended a 6 weeks Android App Development Training from Internshala (An Online Learning Platform) – Created an Android Application named ECHO(a music player) for various Android devices

JAVA CERTIFICATION

Attended a 6 weeks Java(Core) Summer Training at IFCA-Verma Institute, Kashipur (An ISO9001:2008 Certified Institute)

CAREER EDGE CERTIFICATION BY TCS-ION

A 15 days self-paced online certification course on TCS ION (Digital Learning Hub) which aimed at developing soft and hard skills demanded by Industry.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (HONS.)

Galgotias University

08/2016 - 07/2020

Greater Noida, India

Stream

Computer Science & Engineering: 8.82 CGPA

ACHIEVEMENTS

Star Team Award

Multiple Star Team Award Recognition from Business with 100% CSS

District level Swimming Competition

Runner-up at District level Swimming Competition (Under 14 category) in 2012